<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wenyao Liu</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wenyao Liu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wenyaoliu.com&#34;&gt;Wenyao Liu&lt;/a&gt; 
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1. Spatial-temporal Analysis on Connected Vehicle Data for Improving Transportation Safety</title>
      <link>/projects/2022-05-24-1-spatial-temporal-analysis-on-connected-vehicle-data-for-improving-transportation-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2022-05-24-1-spatial-temporal-analysis-on-connected-vehicle-data-for-improving-transportation-safety/</guid>
      <description>**Note: The project is undergoing and some details cannot be provided.**Introduction This undergoing project aims to reveal traffic patterns in sensor data from thousands of connected vehicles in Oklahoma and investigate their correlation with roadway crashes.
Methods  Using Apache Spark for processing and filtering the big data sets (489 GB in total). Visualized vehicle data with ArcGIS and identified traffic and crash data hot spots. Building CNN-based deep learning models and Bayesian hierarchy models (BHM) for predicting roadway crashes based on corresponding vehicular data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Similarity Checking on Four Speed Measurment Systems in Oklahoma</title>
      <link>/projects/02-odot-similarity-checking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/02-odot-similarity-checking/</guid>
      <description>**Note: The project is undergoing and some details cannot be provided.**  Introduction Accurately measure the traffic speed on pavement network it is vital to decision making in transportation system. Four speed measurment systems are available in Oklahoma and their compabilty is unknown.
Featured results 1. Viualize the site/segment in different systems  Fig. 1 Speed measurement location comparisons
 2. Compare the similarity between 4 systems site by site  Fig. 2 Similarity factors between 4 systems site by site (-1 to 1, with 1 as the best)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal Papers</title>
      <link>/publications/01-journal-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/01-journal-papers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;12 peer-reviewed journal papers have been published in total, where I served as key contributor in 6 SCI indexed papers and as paticipator in other 6 papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 more papers were under review and 2 others in preparation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Reports and Proposals</title>
      <link>/publications/02-project-and-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/02-project-and-reports/</guid>
      <description>Reports:   Joshua Q. Li, Kelvin C. P. Wang, Wenyao Liu, and Wenying Yu. 2021. “Utilizing Pavement Friction and Texture Data for the Reduction of Traffic Crashes and Delays.” Final Report FHWA-OK-21-01 (SP&amp;amp;R 2309). Oklahoma Department of Transportation (ODOT), Oklahoma City, OK.
  Joshua Q. Li, Kelvin C. P. Wang, Wenying Yu, Wenyao Liu. 2020. “Continuous Friction Measurement Equipment (CFME) for Highway Safety Management in Oklahoma.” Final Report FHWA-OK-20-02 (SP&amp;amp;R 2306). Oklahoma Department of Transportation (ODOT), Oklahoma City, OK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Utilizing Pavement Friction Data for the Reduction of Traffic Crashes</title>
      <link>/projects/03-odot-2309-friction-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/03-odot-2309-friction-safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by the Oklahoma Department of Transportation (ODOT), this study identifies the contributing factors to traffic crashes and provides decision-making models.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posters and Presentations</title>
      <link>/publications/04-posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/04-posters/</guid>
      <description>10 posters and presentations in total, with one awarded best poster (2nd place) in 2020 Oklahoma Transportation Research Day (OTRD) Poster Competition.
 Wenyao Liu, Joshua Qiang Li, Hamed Gholizadeh (2021). “Utilization of UAV for Estimating Cut and Fill in Roadway Construction and Design.” The 2021 Oklahoma Transportation Symposium. July 27th, 2021. Oklahoma City, OK. (Poster Presentation) Wenyao Liu, Joshua Qiang Li, Xue Yang, Guangwei Yang, Kelvin Wang (2021). “Pavement Condition Assessment Utilizing Smartphone and Vehicle Sensor Data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Peridynamics-based Simulation of Asphalt Mixture Cracking in Semi-circular Bending (SCB) Test</title>
      <link>/projects/04-peridynamics-simulation-scb-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/04-peridynamics-simulation-scb-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peridynamics model was applied to simulate SCB testing for asphalt mixtures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cracking patterns in simulation match lab observations well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fracture energy and P-u curve from simulation agrees with experimental results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arch effect and energy transformation during SCB testing were investigated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patents</title>
      <link>/publications/03-patents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/03-patents/</guid>
      <description>  Wenyao Liu (2018). Bike Saddle Capable of Being Turned Over for Replacement. China Invention Patent.
  Wenyao Liu (2016). A Moving-object Article Management System. China Unity Model Patent.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
